And here, once more we find ourselves in our favorite place, the Jupyter Lab.
우리가 좋아하는 장소에 다시 모였네요 주피터 연구소
Ready to go with weeks.
몇 주 준비됐죠
Week two's exercises.
둘째 주에는 운동하고요
So we go into week two folder and we open up week two, day one.
2주 차 폴더로 가서 2주 차 첫날을 열어보죠
Uh, and here we go.
자, 시작할게요
So a reminder that in week one we used uh multiple frontier LMS through the chat user interface, a
첫째 주에 다중 프런티어 LMS를 사용했죠 채팅방 사용자 인터페이스를 통해서요 웹을 통한
way to use it through the web, uh, and then through the API, we connect it to OpenAI's API.
사용법이죠 API를 통해 OpenAI API에 연결했어요
So today we're going to add to the mix the APIs for Anthropic and Google to join with our skills of
그래서 오늘은 안트로픽과 구글의 API를 통합해 오픈AI 사용 기술에 추가할
using OpenAI.
거예요
Uh, so as a one more reminder, you're going to kill me for keeping going on about this.
다시 한번 말씀드리지만 계속 그 얘기 하면 절 죽이실 거잖아요
This is where you set up your keys.
여기에 열쇠를 꽂아두죠
Uh, you can set up keys for OpenAI, which presumably you already did last week, uh, for anthropic
오픈라이 키를 설정할 수 있죠 아마 지난주에 이미 했겠죠 인류애
and for Gemini for Google.
키와 구글 제미니 키를요
Uh, but, uh, bearing in mind that there is more of an adventure to be had in setting up your Google
하지만 구글 키를 설정하는 데 더 많은 모험이 있다는 걸 명심하세요
Once you've set them up, you create.
설정이 끝나면 창조하는 거죠
You should already have created the file called.
파일을 생성했어야 해요
Env and make sure that your keys are in there in that form.
그 형태로 열쇠가 있는지 확인하세요
If you wish, instead of doing that, you can do it by typing your keys in these cells.
그렇게 하는 대신 이 셀에서 키를 입력하면 돼요
It's it's possible to do it that way.
그렇게 할 수 있어요
It's not recommended for security reasons.
보안상 권장할 수 없는 일이죠
In case you one day make this public and then other people will see your keys.
언젠가 이걸 공개해서 다른 사람들이 열쇠를 보게 되면요
All right, enough preamble.
서론은 그만하죠
Let's run some imports.
수입품 검사를 해 보죠
Let's run this block of code here that sets the environment variables.
환경 변수를 설정하는 코드 블록을 실행해보죠
You're pretty familiar with this.
잘 아시네요
And now in this cell, you can see that I make the same call to OpenAI to, to establish that connection
이 셀에서 오픈AI API 연결을 설정하기 위해 OpenAI에
to the OpenAI API that you're familiar with now.
같은 전화를 걸었어요
But then I have something pretty similar for Claude and then something a little bit different for Google
클로드 비트도 비슷하고 제미니 비트는 구글에서 약간 다르게
for Gemini.
만들었죠
So these are the sort of, uh, semi somewhat analogous commands that we're using for those three.
이런 식으로 반이나 어느 정도 비슷한 명령을 이 세 가지에 사용하고 있어요
Okay.
네
So we've seen a bunch of things that Llms are pretty good at, and then just a few things where it tripped
Lms가 잘하는 것들을 많이 보았고 몇 가지 실행되는 것들을 보았습니다 하지만 대부분은 Lms가
up, but mostly things that it's very good at.
잘하는 것들이죠
One of the things that it's not so good at as it would happen, is telling jokes.
한 가지 잘 안 되는 건 농담을 하는 거예요
When you give it a very tight, uh, context in which it has to try and form that joke.
아주 딱 맞는 문맥을 주면 그 안에서 농담을 구성해야 해요
Uh, and so, you know, this is clearly not a very commercial example, but it's a way of having some
이건 상업적인 예는 아니지만 재미를 위한 방법이고
fun and getting some experience with the APIs.
API로 경험을 쌓는 거죠
Uh, we are going to ask some llms to tell jokes over the API.
API 상에서 농담을 해 줄 llms를 모실 거예요
Um, so what information do you do?
어떤 정보를 제공하죠?
You send over an API.
API 하나를 보내죠
Typically, you always specify the name of the model that you want to use.
일반적으로 사용하고 싶은 모델의 이름을 항상 지정해요
You typically give the system message and the user message.
시스템 메시지와 사용자 메시지를 주로 제공하죠
You're super familiar with this now system message giving the overall context.
전반적인 컨텍스트를 제공하는 시스템 메시지에 아주 익숙하죠
The user message is the actual prompt.
사용자 메시지가 실제 프롬프트죠
Um, and there are some other characteristics.
다른 특징도 있어요
There are some other things that you can do.
다른 방법도 있어요
You can pass in something called the temperature which is between 0 and 1, usually where one means
온도라는 걸 통과시킬 수 있어요 0에서 1 사이죠 보통 좀 더 무작위적인
I want a more random creative output Outputs, and zero would be the lowest possible focused, deterministic
창의적 출력 출력을 뜻합니다 0은 가장 가능성이 낮은 집중된 결정론적 반복 가능 설정이고요
So that is another parameter that you can often provide.
여러분이 제공할 수 있는 또 다른 매개 변수죠
So in this case we're going to set a system message to be you are an assistant that is great at telling
이 경우에 시스템 메시지를 설정하겠습니다 농담을 잘 하는 비서라고 하는
jokes.
거죠
And the user prompt will be tell a light hearted joke for an audience of data scientists.
데이터 과학자들을 위해 가벼운 농담을 할 거예요
That would be you and also me.
당신과 내가 되겠죠
Okay, so then this structure here is hopefully something very familiar to you.
여기 이 구조는 여러분에게 아주 익숙하길 바라요
This is where we put the prompts into a list to elements you a system and a user as the as the role
여기서 프롬프트들을 목록에 넣습니다. 요소들, 시스템, 사용자를 역할로 for each each each each each요.
in these two elements.
이 두 요소에서요.
Going into this list, I hopefully don't need to explain it because you're now quite familiar with this.
이 리스트를 살펴보면, 설명하지 않아도 될 것 같네요. 이제 익숙해졌으니까요.
Uh, as I say, this, this, this, um, value here, the role can be system or user.
말씀드렸듯이 이 값은 여기 이 역할이 시스템 또는 유저가 될 수 있어요
You're going to find out later.
곧 알게 될 거예요
It can also be assistant.
조수라고도 할 수 있죠
So it can be system user or assistant.
시스템 사용자나 보조가 될 수 있죠
And then later this week you're going to find some other thing that can go in there as well.
그리고 이번 주 후반에는 다른 것도 넣을 수 있을 거예요
So.
그래서요?
But for now, all you need to remember is system and user as the two roles we're going to be using.
하지만 지금은 시스템과 사용자를 우리가 사용할 두 역할로 기억해야 해요
So we put that into the list of prompts.
그래서 그걸 Put 프롬프트 목록에 넣었어요
And I should remember to execute the cell before it.
그 전에 감옥을 처리해야 하고요
Before I do that did I execute the cell here.
그 전에 이 감방을 실행했어요
Yes I did all right.
네, 괜찮았어요
Here we go.
시작할게요
Let's try that one again.
다시 해 보죠
Execute that cell.
저 감방을 처형해요
Execute this cell.
이 감방을 실행해요
Very good okay.
좋아요
Let's start with one of the older GPT models GPT 3.5 turbo, which quite recently was like the the latest
오래된 GPT 모델부터 살펴보죠 GPT 3 5 터보 엔진인데 최근에 나온 최고의 개척
and greatest frontier model.
모델이죠
But it's already old news.
하지만 이미 지난 일이에요
But we will use this.
하지만 이걸 쓸 거예요
And so the API, which now you're quite familiar with for OpenAI is OpenAI dot chat, dot completions,
오픈AI에서 이제 익숙해진 API는 OpenAI.챗, .완성 .Creetions,
dot create completions, um, being the name of this, this API, the one that basically takes an existing
.Create 완성 이 API의 이름이죠 기존 프롬프트 모음을 가져다가 대화를 완성하기
set of prompts and then tries to complete generate text to complete the conversation.
위해 텍스트 생성을 시도하는 거예요
Um, and as we call create, we pass in a model and we pass in the messages in the format that you're
생성을 통해 모델과 메시지를 전달합니다 여러분이 익숙한 형식으로 전달하죠
So let's see.
어디 보죠
And you remember when we get back the response, what we do is we take completion dot choices, which
응답을 받았을 때 우리가 하는 건 완료 .선택입니다 가능한
is a list of possible choices.
선택 목록이죠
But there will only be one element in there.
하지만 한 가지 요소만 넣을 거예요
There is a way that you can specify that you want it to return multiple choices.
여러 개의 선택을 반환하도록 지정할 수 있는 방법이 있어요
But since we haven't done that, we just get back one and it's in location zero of course.
하지만 아직 안 했으니 get get을 하면 당연히 0위치에 있죠
So completion dot choices zero dot message gives us back the message and content returns it in a string.
완료 .선택 .0.Message는 메시지를 반환하고 콘텐츠는 문자열로 반환하죠
So that is what we get back and we print it.
그걸 get 해 프린트하는 거죠
And now let's see what kind of joke.
어떤 장난인지 볼까요?
For data scientists GPT 3.5 turbo can come up with.
데이터 과학자인 GPT 3을 위해서요 5 터보로 할 수 있어요
Here we go.
시작할게요
Why did the data scientists break up with their computer?
왜 데이터 과학자들이 컴퓨터와 분리했을까요?
It just couldn't handle their complex relationship.
둘의 복잡한 관계를 감당하지 못했죠
Okay, okay.
알았어요
You know, I get it, I see it.
Get it, I'm get it, I'm get it, I'm get it, I'm get it, I'm get it, I'm get it, I'm get it, I'm get it, I'm get it.
It's not the world's funniest joke, but it's not terrible.
세상에서 가장 웃긴 농담은 아니지만 끔찍하지도 않아요
You know, the data scientists model relationships between things and couldn't handle their complex
데이터 과학자들은 사물의 관계를 모델로 삼지만 그 복잡한 관계를 다룰
relationship.
수 없어요
Fair enough.
좋아요
I'd say that's a perfectly acceptable, acceptable joke coming from GPT 3.5 turbo.
GPT 3에서 나온 농담치고는 아주 괜찮은데요 5 터보요
So let's see if GPT four mini can do better.
GPT 4 미니는 더 잘할 수 있을까요?
This time, we're going to just slightly expand our use of the API.
이번엔 API 사용을 살짝 확장할게요
I'm including temperature, so this is where you can pass in this number between 0 and 1.
온도도 포함해서 0에서 1 사이의 숫자를 입력할 수 있어요
One for the most creative, zero for the least.
창의성은 1점, 최저점은 0점이죠
Um, and uh, out of this I have completion choices zero message content.
이 중엔 완료 선택지와 메시지 콘텐츠도 없어요
Again, you should be very familiar with this.
이것도 아주 익숙할 거예요
Let's see how it performs.
잘 달리는지 보죠
Why did the data scientist break up with a statistician?
데이터 과학자가 왜 통계학자랑 헤어졌죠?
Because she found him too mean.
너무 못됐다고 생각했거든요
I'd say that's a pretty good joke.
꽤 괜찮은 농담이네요
I'd say that's fine.
괜찮은 것 같아요
That's that's, uh, that's an acceptable joke.
그 정도는 괜찮은 농담이죠
Maybe I was harsh when I said that llms aren't very good at this, because that's a perfectly decent
llm은 이런 농담 잘 못한다고 한 게 너무 심했나 봐요 그 정도면 괜찮은 농담인데요
Uh, and, uh, I think we will give GPT four a mini, uh, a round of applause for that.
GPT 4에 작은 박수를 보내 줘야 할 것 같네요
Okay, let's try GPT four Minis, uh, bigger cousin, GPT four.
GPT 4 미니와 더 큰 사촌인 GPT 4를 써 보죠
Oh, the maxi version of GPT four.
GPT 4의 맥시 버전이네요
Oh, the big guy.
덩치 큰 친구요
And we will ask it.
우리가 물어볼 거예요
Let's give it the same temperature so we're not messing with things as we go.
온도는 똑같이 유지해야 해요 그래야 실수가 없죠
We'll ask it for it for a joke.
농담 삼아 물어보죠
Two and let's see how it does.
둘, 어떻게 되나 보죠
Why did the data scientist go broke?
데이터 과학자가 왜 파산했죠?
Because they couldn't find any cache in their array.
어레이에서 캐시를 못 찾았거든요
If it hadn't put on in their array, I might have found that better.
Get up이 아니었다면 더 나았을 거예요
I don't, uh, couldn't find any cache.
캐시는 못 찾았어요
Would be okay.
괜찮을 거예요
Maybe I'm missing something here.
내가 뭘 놓쳤나 봐요
I I'm not sure I get it.
Get me get it, I'm get it, I'm get it, I'm get it, I'm get it, I'm get it, I'm get it, I'm get it, I'm get it, I'm get it, I'm get it, I'm get it, I'm get it, I'm get it, I'm get it, I'm get it, I'm get'm it, I'm it'm it'm get'm it, I'm it'm it'm get'm it'm it'm it'm it're
Uh, let's try another one.
다른 걸 해 보죠
Let's do what I had in there before and start pulling the temperature down a bit, see what we get.
아까 했던 대로 비트 온도를 낮춰서 어떻게 되는지 보죠 get it
Why did scientists break up with the logistic regression model?
왜 과학자들은 물류 회귀 모델과 헤어졌을까요?
Because it couldn't find the right fit.
맞는 걸 못 찾았거든요
Uh, you know, that's perfectly decent.
괜찮은 생각이네요
That's acceptable.
그건 괜찮아요
That's that's maybe, uh, I'm not sure which I prefer between Mini and Maxi, but, uh, that's a that's
미니와 맥시 중에 뭐가 더 좋은지 모르겠지만 꽤
a pretty solid, solid gag there.
튼튼한 개그 소재예요
I think we will we will say that that that's a pass for sure.
이건 확실히 통과라고 할 수 있겠네요
All right.
좋아요
Let's move on to clause 3.5.
3번 조항으로 넘어가죠 5분
Sonnet.
소네트요
Uh, so the API looks strikingly similar.
API가 눈에 띄게 비슷하죠
That's the good news.
좋은 소식이죠
It's basically very, very similar indeed.
기본적으로 아주 비슷해요
A couple of differences.
차이점이 몇 가지 있어요
You do have to pass in the system message as its own separate attribute.
시스템 메시지를 개별 특성으로 전달해야 해요
And then the messages is again this this list of decks.
메시지는 다시 이 데크 목록이에요
But of course it doesn't have that first entry for the system message because you've already passed
물론 시스템 메시지의 첫 항목은 없어요 이미 별도로 넘겼으니까요
Um, so that's a slight difference.
그건 미묘한 차이죠
Um, also, Max tokens is something which is optional for the OpenAI API to to specify the, the maximum
최대 토큰은 오픈AI API 선택 사항으로 최대 토큰의 수를 지정하는 데 사용되죠
And I believe it's actually required for Claude.
클로드도 그래야 할 거예요
So that's why it's in here.
그래서 여기 들어있군요
But otherwise everything should look very similar.
하지만 그 외에는 전부 비슷해 보여야 해요
The API itself is a little bit easier to memorize.
API 자체는 외우기가 좀 더 쉬워요 비트
It's just Claude dot messages dot create.
클로드 점 메시지 점 만들기예요
It's slightly shorter, but it's otherwise quite similar to OpenAI ChatGPT completions create.
약간 짧지만 오픈AI 챗GPT 완성본과 상당히 비슷해요
Uh, so there it is.
저기 있네요
And then when we get back a response, it's message content zero.
응답이 오면 메시지 콘텐츠 get이 0이 되죠
Again, you're asking for the the first one, but we're only going to get back one because we've only
첫 번째 것만 요청하는데 하나만 나올 거예요 왜냐하면 .text만
asked for one dot text gives us that's the equivalent of dot content for OpenAI.
요청했거든요 OpenAI의 .content와 같은 거죠
So let's see.
어디 보죠
This is a useful hopefully for you for for the API framework for Claude.
클로드의 API 프레임워크에 유용하면 좋겠네요
Let's see now how Claude does with a joke.
클로드가 농담을 어떻게 하는지 보죠
Sure.
네
Here's a lighthearted joke for data scientists.
데이터 과학자들을 위한 가벼운 농담이 있어요
Why do data scientists break up with their significant other?
데이터 과학자들은 왜 사랑하는 사람과 헤어질까요?
They just was too much variance in the relationship, and they couldn't find a good way to normalize
관계에 너무 많은 변화가 있었고 그걸 정상화할 좋은 방법을 찾지 못했어요
Uh, yeah, that's all right.
네, 괜찮아요
I'd say it's a nerdier it's a slightly more, uh, um, data sciency.
좀 더 너디스러운 것 같아요 데이터 과학에 가깝죠
It's perhaps just a tiny bit less funny, but it's not bad at all.
비트만 조금 less지만 나쁘지 않아요
I don't know, I think whether you prefer that to GPT four is probably a matter of taste.
글쎄요, GPT 4보다 그게 더 좋은지는 취향의 문제겠죠
They're perfectly solid jokes.
완벽한 농담이죠
They're not explosively funny, but I'd say perfectly solid.
폭발할 만큼 웃기진 않지만 아주 튼튼해요
Not terrible.
나쁘지 않아요
Um.
네
Anyway, the point of this is more about APIs and about jokes, although it always keeps it entertaining.
어쨌든 핵심은 API와 농담에 관한 겁니다 늘 재미있긴 하지만요
What I want to show you now is about streaming.
지금부터 보여드릴 건 스트리밍에 관한 거예요
Um, you remember we talked briefly about streaming before the streaming example?
스트리밍 예시를 보기 전에 스트리밍에 대해 잠깐 얘기했었죠?
We did before, uh, looked a bit complicated because we had to deal with the fact that we were bringing
전에 했던 건 좀 복잡해 보였어요 비트코인 가격 인하를 다시
back markdown and we had to to handle that markdown.
해야 하고 그 가격 인하에 대처해야 했으니까요
This looks a bit simpler because we're not dealing with with a markdown response.
마크다운 비트를 다루는 게 아니라서 더 간단해 보이죠
We're going to ask the same model, cloud 3.5 again for a joke, but this time we're going to stream
같은 모델인 클라우드 3에 질문할게요 다시 5가 나왔네요 이번엔 결과를 스트리밍할게요
So you may remember when we asked OpenAI to stream the way we did it is we just added another attribute
오픈AI에 스트림하라고 요청했을 때 다른 특성 스트림이 true인 것을 추가한 것을
stream equals true.
기억하시나요?
And that meant that it was in streaming mode.
그건 스트리밍 모드였다는 뜻이죠
For Claude, it's slightly different.
클로드는 조금 다르죠
There is no extra attribute.
추가 속성은 없어요
Instead, you call the dot stream method instead of the dot create method.
.Stream 메서드를 호출해요 .Create 메서드 대신에요
So slightly different approach there.
접근법이 약간 달라요
That's a nuance of difference between anthropic and OpenAI for streaming.
인도적인 것과 오픈AI의 스트리밍은 차이가 있어요
So we call Claude messages stream.
클로드 메시지의 흐름이라고 부르기로 했어요
Otherwise it's the same.
그 외에는 똑같아요
And then with what comes back, we use a context manager with results as stream.
돌아온 결과로는 스트림으로서의 결과를 가진 컨텍스트 관리자를 사용하죠
Um, and then it's for text in stream text stream.
스트림 텍스트 스트림의 텍스트죠
And you remember OpenAI was was for chunk in response.
오픈아이는 그에 대한 답장이었죠
So OpenAI was a bit different again in the way that you read back results.
오픈AI는 비트 백 결과를 읽는 방식이 조금 달랐어요
But there it is.
하지만 저기 있네요
We get each little chunk back and just going to print that chunk.
각각의 덩어리를 get 해 프린트하죠
Um, and the reason for this is to make sure that it doesn't print each chunk on a separate line.
이렇게 하는 이유는 한 줄에 한 덩어리가 찍히지 않도록 하기 위해서죠
Otherwise it'd be very hard to read.
안 그러면 읽기 힘들었을 거예요
So this should look better.
이게 더 보기 좋을 거예요
Let's see how Claude 3.5 sonnet does with a joke that it will then stream back to us in JupyterLab.
클로드 3을 보죠 농담과 함께 소네트 5개가 유피터랩에서 스트리밍될 거예요
There we go.
됐어요
You see?
봤죠?
It's streaming.
스트리밍이에요
Sure, here's a light hearted joke for Data Scientist.
데이터 사이언스에게는 가벼운 농담이 있죠
Why did that same joke?
왜 똑같은 농담을 해요?
It seems exactly the same joke, but it's added in a Brahms little drum.
똑같은 농담 같지만 브람스 드럼에 추가된 거죠
Uh, explosion at the end, which is nice.
마지막에 폭발하는 게 좋았어요
I wonder why did I ask for more tokens than before?
왜 전보다 패를 더 많이 달라고 했을까요?
Let's see.
어디 보죠
No.
아뇨
The same.
똑같아요
Um, it's.
네
And it gives a little explanation.
설명이 나오죠
This joke plays on statistical concepts which are common to data science.
이 농담은 데이터 과학에서 흔한 통계 개념을 이용한 거예요
It's a bit nerdy, but should get a chuckle from data savvy audience.
좀 따분하지만 데이터에 밝은 관객들은 웃을 거예요 Get it
Well, I would say you guys are a data savvy audience, so you can be the judge of that.
데이터에 밝은 분들이니 판단해 주실 수 있겠죠
Did it get a chuckle from you?
Get it, Get it, Get it, Get it, Get, Get, Get, Get, Get 웃었어요?
Moving on.
넘어가죠
Gemini has a different structure.
제미니는 구조가 달라요
It's it's quite a bit different, actually.
사실 비트는 좀 달라요
Um, and I'd probably say to Google's credit, their ability to set up tokens is much more complicated,
구글 크레딧은 토큰을 설정하는 기능이 훨씬 복잡하지만 API 설정은
but the API is a bit simpler.
좀 더 간단해요
Uh, you can see here you create a generative model object and you pass in the name of the model, we'll
여기 보이는 것처럼 모델 객체를 생성해서 모델 이름을 입력해요 제미니 1호를
use the Gemini 1.5 flash.
쓸 거예요 5번 섬광이에요
You remember how many how large the context window is for Gemini 1.5 flash.
제미니 1호의 경우 얼마나 큰 문맥 창문이 필요했는지 기억하시죠? 5번 섬광이에요
Can you remember that?
기억할 수 있겠어요?
It was top of the table that we had before?
전에 있던 테이블 위였나요?
It was a remarkable 1 million tokens.
놀랍게도 백만 토큰이었죠
A million tokens.
백만 토큰요
750,000 words.
750,000단어요
So, Gemini 1.5 flash.
제미니 1호예요 5번 섬광이에요
We pass in the system instruction when we create this object, and then we call Gemini dot.
이 객체를 만들 때 시스템 지시를 전달해요 제미니 닷이라고 부르죠
Generate content with the user prompt.
사용자 프롬프트에서 콘텐츠를 생성하세요
And it's just response dot text.
응답 .text예요
So a little bit less futzing around with both the request and the response here it's a bit of a simpler
요청과 응답 둘 다에서 좀 덜 빈둥거리죠 API가 좀 더 간단해요 하지만
API, but let's see the quality of joke.
비트의 질을 보죠
Importantly, why did the data scientists break up with a statistician?
중요한 건, 데이터 과학자들이 왜 통계 전문가와 헤어졌느냐죠
Because they couldn't see eye to eye on the p value.
P 값에 대한 견해가 달랐기 때문이죠
Ah.
네
Well, uh, I see the data science side of it.
전 데이터 과학 쪽을 봐요
I'm not sure I get it.
Get you get. 잘 모르겠어요
Hahaha.
네
Uh, maybe you do get it.
Get it, get it, get it! 이해하실지도 모르겠네요
And I'm being being, uh, being dozy.
전 졸린 것 같아요
Uh, in which case, by all means pointed out to me.
그런 경우라면 어떻게든 절 가리키겠죠
But I don't particularly get the funny aspect of that joke.
근데 그 농담의 재밌는 면을 잘 모르겠어요 Get it
So for me, I would say that, uh, Gemini certainly lags in terms of its, uh, Gemini 1.5 flash in
그래서 제 생각에는 제미니 1호가 확실히 뒤처졌다고 봐요 유머 면에서 말이죠
All right.
좋아요
Anyways, to get serious for a moment, let's go back to GPT four.
아무튼 본격적으로 GPT 4로 돌아가 보죠
Many with the original question.
다들 같은 질문을 했죠
You're a helpful assistant.
정말 도움이 되는 조수네요
How do I decide if a business problem is suitable for an LLM solution?
사업상의 문제가 LLM 해결책에 적합한지 어떻게 판단하죠?
Remember, that was the very first question we asked through the chat interface.
채팅 인터페이스를 통해 가장 먼저 받은 질문이었죠
Um, and we can now bring this together again.
이제 다시 합칠 수 있어요
This should be pretty familiar to you.
이런 거 익숙하죠?
We're going to stream back the results in markdown.
가격 인하 결과를 스트리밍으로 보여드릴게요
So it's OpenAI chat dot completions dot create.
OpenAI 채팅 .완료 .Create죠
We pass in the model.
모델을 통과시키죠
We're going to go for the big guy.
큰 녀석을 노릴 거예요
Um we use the prompts.
프롬프트도 사용해요
We set a temperature.
온도를 설정했어요
We say stream equals true.
스트리밍은 true라고 하죠
That's the way that you do it with OpenAI.
오픈아이는 이렇게 요리해요
Um, and then this is the way that we stream back the results again.
그리고 이런 식으로 결과를 다시 스트리밍하죠
It's a little bit more involved because we're dealing with markdown.
비트 박스를 줄이는 중이라 좀 더 복잡해요
And so we have to do some, some sort of, uh, special stuff here to basically refresh the markdown
그래서 우린 여기서 특별한 작업을 해야 합니다 각 반복에서 마크다운을 새로
with each iteration.
고침하기 위해서요
If you're not sure we have to do it this way, try taking that out and doing it differently, and you'll
이렇게 해야 하는지 확신이 안 들면 저걸 빼고 다르게 해 보세요
immediately see what what what happens.
그럼 바로 어떻게 되는지 보일 거예요
It it won't look good.
보기 안 좋을 거예요
Uh, and let's run that.
그걸 실행해 보죠
And here we get the results, and you can see that it looks great.
get get 결과가 나왔네요. 아주 좋아 보이죠.
You can see some of the flicking happening when the markdown has only partially come through.
일부만 뚫렸을 때 튕기는 게 보이죠
And so it's interpreting things like when there's perhaps multiple hashes representing a subheading.
즉 부제목을 나타내는 여러 개의 해시를 해석하는 것이죠
And it's only received one hash and it thinks there's a big heading coming.
해시 하나만 받았는데 큰 게 오는 줄 아나 봐요
Uh, at least I think that's what we were seeing there briefly, with some of that flickering as the
마크다운이 일어나면서 깜빡이는 현상이 잠깐 있었던
markdown appeared.
것 같아요
But at the end of it we get back, of course, a very nicely constructed response, well structured,
하지만 마지막에 우린 아주 잘 구성된 응답을 얻습니다 잘 구조화되어 마크다운
and it's formatted perfectly in markdown streams back.
스트림 백에서 완벽한 포맷이죠
All right.
좋아요
So that has given you a sense of the different APIs and a bit of messing around with some, some fun
다양한 API에 대한 감각을 얻었고 재미있는 질문도 비트 박스를 좀 어지럽혔죠
And what we're going to do next in the next video is actually have a couple of llms talk to each other,
다음 비디오에서 할 것은 몇 개의 llms가 서로 대화하는 겁니다 재미있을
which should be fun.
거예요
I will see you then.
그때 봐요